Brice Shatzer

www.BriceShatzer.com

brice.shatzer@gmail.com 319-239-2470

Chicago-based technologist with a decade of experience building software for businesses of all sizes. Skilled in crafting both delightful user-facing interactions & pragmatic solutions, with a passion for the administrative and organizational processes around the craft of software development.

Tools & Technologies

- React
- Next.js
- Node.js + Express.js
- Backbone.is + Marionette
- Svelte / Vue.js

- "Vanilla" HTML, CSS,
 & Javascript
- TypesScript / Flow
- SASS / LESS
- Git / Mercurial / SVN
- Jest, Mocha, Jasmine, Enzyme, Puppeteer, & Karma
- Webpack, Babel, Rollup, Grunt, & Gulp

Recent Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer — W.W. Grainger, Inc.

October 2021 - Present

• Part of the Core Engineering team that is responsible for building, documenting, & supporting the design system & various other tools that are relied upon by various teams across the 1000+ person engineering organization. This team has been responsible for saving over 5400 hours of engineering work since I've joined.

Senior Software Engineer — PayPal

July 2020 - August 2021

- Part of the Checkout Integrations team that worked on the company's flagship service which handles \$100+B in payment volumes across 200+ countries for millions of active users a month
- Primary developer and point of contact for our "Pay w/ Venmo" desktop solution, enabling users to generate a QR Code that allows them to complete the checkout process via their mobile device
- Generated & updated documentation around the various tools and libraries that are used both internally and made available to the open source community

Software Engineer — Onion Inc. | G/O Media

September 2017 - April 2020

- Part of the team that worked on Kinja, the CMS powering some of the internet's favorite sites like Gizmodo, Lifehacker, Kotaku, and The Onion; reaching 85-100 million active users a month
- Helped migrate and rewrite our core platform from a Scala w/ Closure templates back-end & Backbone + Marionette front-end to Isomorphic JavaScript (Express & React)

Full Work History

Software Engineer

February 2016 - April 2017

Doejo — Digital agency that specialized in serving enterprise WordPress VIP clients

Web Developer II

September 2015 - February 2016

GoHealth — One of the leading digital health insurance marketplaces

UI/Front-End Developer

November 2014 - September 2015

Packback — SharkTank-funded startup creating a platform for digital textbook rentals

Web Developer/Designer

April 2012 - July 2014

Links Technology Solutions — Agency providing custom web & software solutions

Education